Stewart L. Udall papers, 1950-2010
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
- Series II: Department of the Interior, 1961-1972
  - Department of the Interior, 1965-1966
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies. January-March 1965 (Box 124, Folder 1)
      Remarks of Stewart Udall before the House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs regarding the Programs of the Department, Washington, DC, January 26, 1965
      American Association of School Administrators Convention, Atlantic City, New Jersey, February 14, 1965
      Sales Executives Club of New York. See Box 196: Honors and Rewards, February 23, 1965
      National Reclamation Association Board of Directors Meeting, Washington, DC, February 24, 1965
      Dedication of Job Corps Conservation Center, Catoctin Mountain Park, Thurmont, Maryland, February 27, 1965
      University of Arizona Founders’ Day Convocation, Tucson, Arizona, March 12, 1965. See Box 196: Honors & Awards,
      Harvard-Yale-Princeton Clubs Luncheon, Washington, DC, March 16, 1965
      National Rifle Association Meeting, Washington, DC, March 28, 1965.
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies-Inauguration of President Lyndon B. Johnson: Also Copy (#18 of a Limited Edition) of Inaugural 1965, the Official Book of the Inauguration. January 20, 1965 (Box 124, Folder 2)
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies- Downtown Progress Annual Meeting,Washington, DC. January 27, 1965 (Box 124, Folder 3)
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & CeremoniesBus and Walking Tour of the Potomac River, Washington, DC Area. March 2, 1965 (Box 124, Folder 4)
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies. April-May 1965 (Box 124, Folder 5)
      American Newspaper Women’s Club, Washington, DC, April 1, 1965
      An Evening of Art with the American Indian,Washington, DC, April 21, 1965
      Dedication of Olmsted Island, Great Fall, Potomac River, Maryland, April 22, 1965
      Sunday Sermon by Stewart Udall, All Souls Unitarian Church,Washington, DC, May 2, 1965
      Boat Trip down the Potomac River to Mount Vernon,Washington, DC, May 5, 1965
      Signing Ceremony of the Proclamation adding Ellis Island to the Liberty Island National Monument, White House, May 11, 1965
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies-Lighting of Japanese Lantern, to Open the Cherry Blossom Festival, Washington, DC. April 6, 1965 (Box 124, Folder 6)
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies-White House Conference on Natural Beauty, Washington, DC. May 24-25, 1965 (Box 124, Folder 7)
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies. June 1965 (Box 124, Folder 8)
      Arizona State University Commencement, Tempe, Arizona, June 1, 1965. See Box 196: Honors & Awards
      Tour of New York City with Robert Kennedy regarding Neighborhood Parks, June 7, 1965
      Long Island University Commencement, Brooklyn, New York, June 8, 1965. See Box 196: Honors & Awards
      Political Speech and Reception,York, Pennsylvania, June 10, 1965
      Dartmouth College Commencement, Hanover, New Hampshire, June 13, 1965. See Box 196: Honors & Awards
      Springfield College Commencement, Springfield, Massachusetts, June 13, 1965. See Box 196: Honors & Awards
      LBJ’s Festival of the Arts, White House, June 14, 1965
      AIA Convention, Pan American Congress, Washington, DC, June 17, 1965
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies-Dedication of the Pope-Leighey Frank Lloyd Wright House,Woodlawn, Virginia. June 16, 1965 (Box 124, Folder 9)
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies-Population Conference, Aspen, California. June 17-19, 1965 (Box 124, Folder 10)
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies. July 1965 (Box 124, Folder 11)
      Trip to the Grand Tetons and Snake River Float with Japanese Officials, Wyoming, July 9-10, 1965
      Luncheon honoring Members of the Japanese Cabinet, White House, July 14, 1965
      Thirteenth Anniversary of the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico Celebration, San Juan, Puerto Rico, July 25, 1965
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies-Presentation of National Landmark Plaque for the Colonial Annapolis Historic District, Annapolis, Maryland. July 7, 1965 (Box 124, Folder 12)
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies-Memorial Service for Adlai E. Stevenson, Washington, DC. July 16, 1965 (Box 124, Folder 13)
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies-Visit to Iowa and Illinois Political Speeches, Hike Along the Illinois-Mississippi Canal, and Visit to Old Fort Madison. July 23, 1965 (Box 124, Folder 14)
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies. August 1965 (Box 124, Folder 15)
      Visit to Saline Water Conservation Plant with 29 Foreign Ambassadors, Freeport, Texas, August 4, 1965
      Acceptance of the Department of the Interior’s Safety Award, Capitol Building, Washington, DC, August 17, 1965
      National Historic Landmark Ceremony, New Harmony, Indiana, August 21, 1965
      International Water Quality Exposition, Washington, DC, August 25, 1965. See Box 203: Honors & Awards (Oversize)
      Visit to Saline Water Conservation Plant with 20 Foreign Ambassadors, Roswell, New Mexico, August 26, 1965
      Governor’s State-wide Conference on Arizona Beautification, Phoenix, Arizona, August 27, 1965
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies. September 1965 (Box 125, Folder 1)
      Signing of Delaware Water Gap National Recreation Area Legislation, White House, September 1, 1965
      75th Anniversary of the Board on Geographic Names, Washington, DC, September 2, 1965.
      400th Anniversary of the Founding of St. Augustine, St. Augustine, Florida, September 5, 1965
      Cruise along the Connecticut River to study pollution problems, Connecticut, September 14, 1965
      Bicentennial Convocation of James Smithson’s Birth, Smithsonian Institution, Washington, DC, September 16, 1965
      National Park Service Superintendents Conference, Gatlinburg, Tennessee, September 17, 1965
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies- Signing Ceremony for Assateague Island National Seashore Park Bill, White House. September 21, 1965 (Box 125, Folder 2)
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies-Trip to Washington, Montana, North Dakota. Political Speeches, Meetings with Students, Indian Groups, Conservation Leaders, Tour of the Badlands. September 29-October 2, 1965 (Box 125, Folder 3)
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies. October 1965 (Box 125, Folder 4)
      First International Symposium on Water Desalination, Washington, DC, October 4, 1965
      Signing Ceremony for US-Mexico Water Agreement, White House, October 7, 1965
      President and Mrs. Johnson’s "Salute to the Congress" Reception, White House, October 7, 1965
      Meeting with Outdoorsmen and Conservationists, Spruce Knob, West Virginia, October 9, 1965
      Arizona Reclamation Association Meeting, Phoenix, Arizona, October 30, 1965
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies-Planting of the "President Johnson Willow Oak" at the Bethesda Naval Hospital, Bethesda, Maryland. October 15, 1965 (Box 125, Folder 5)
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies-Trip to South America, Argentina. October 16-23, 1965 (Box 125, Folder 6)
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies-Trip to South America, Chile. October 16-23, 1965 (Box 125, Folder 7)
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies-Opening Ceremonies at Treasure Lake Job Corps Conservation Center, Speech to Lawton Chamber of Commerce and Other Aactivities, Oklahoma. October 29, 1965 (Box 125, Folder 8)
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies. November-December 1965 (Box 125, Folder 9)
      National Association of Educational Broadcasters Convention, Washington, DC, November 3, 1965.
      Trip to Wisconsin: Conservation tour and speaking engagements on behalf of Democratic candidates, November 7-8, 1965. Includes an air-inspection of the Kettle Moraine, a boat trip of the Wolf River, and discussions about condition of the Menominee Indians. See Also Box 162: Wild and Scenic Rivers, Wolf River, Wisconsin
      General Electric Trip regarding power transmission, Washington, DC, New York, Pennsylvania, November 17-18, 1965
      Dinner honoring Chancellor Ludwig Erhard of the Federal Republic of Germany (White House). December 20, 1965
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies- Trip to Georgia and the Cumberland Islands. November 4-5, 1965 (Box 125, Folder 10)
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies-United Action for Clear Water Conference of the United Automobile Workers, AFL-CIO, Detroit, Michigan. November 6, 1965 (Box 125, Folder 11)
    - Department of the Interior: National Reclamation Association Convention, Kansas City, Missouri. November 10, 1965 (Box 125, Folder 12)
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies-Canadian Club of Toronto, Toronto, Canada. November 15, 1965 (Box 125, Folder 13)
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies-National Association of Home Builders Exposition and Convention, Chicago, Illinois. December 6, 1965 (Box 125, Folder 14)
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies-Christmas Tree Lighting, White House. December 17, 1965 (Box 125, Folder 15)
    - Department of the Interior: 1966 Calendar. 1966 (Box 126, Folder 1)
    - Department of the Interior, 1966: Appointment Schedule. 1966 (Box 126, Folder 2-5)
    - Department of the Interior: Travel Accounts, Fiscal Year 1965/66. 1966 (Box 126, Folder 6)
    - Department of the Interior: Reports to the President. 1966 (Box 126, Folder 7)
    - Department of the Interior: Stewart Udall and President Johnson 1966 (Box 126, Folder 8)
    - Department of the Interior: Stewart Udall and President’s Staff. 1966 (Box 126, Folder 9)
    - Department of the Interior, 1966: Stewart Udall and Staff. 1966 (Box 127, Folder 1)
    - Department of the Interio: Jobs, Appointments, and Letters of Recommendation. 1966 (Box 127, Folder 2)
    - Department of the Interior: Stewart Udall’s Personal and Miscellaneous Correspondence. 1966 (Box 127, Folder 3)
    - Department of the Interior: Photographs: Miscellaneous of Stewart Udall and Others. 1966 (Box 127, Folder 4)
    - Department of the Interior: Bureau of Indian Affairs, Reorganization, etc. 1966 (Box 127, Folder 5)
    - Department of the Interior: Miscellaneous Reports for Various Divisions. 1966 (Box 127, Folder 6)
    - Department of the Interior: Miscellaneous. 1966 (Box 127, Folder 7)
    - Department of the Interior: Politics. 1966 (Box 127, Folder 8)
    - Department of the Interior: Television and Radio Programs (Various). Includes Tape Recording: "This Land Was Made For You and Me," by Frank Hemingway-a Radio-TV Documentary. 1966 (Box 127, Folder 9)
    - Department of the Interior: Radio Program, CBS "Open Mike" Question and Answer Program. Tape Recordings, 2 Reels. May 31, 1966 (Box 127, Folder 10)
    - Department of the Interior: Press Conferences Includes Tape Recording of Conference. 1966 (Box 128, Folder 1-3)
    - Department of the Interior: Cabinet Meetings. 1966 (Box 129, Folder 1)
    - Department of the Interior: Stewart Udall’s Notes and Comments. 1966 (Box 129, Folder 2)
    - Department of the Interior: President’s Special Message on the Quality of Environment (Water Pollution, etc.). February 23, 1966 (Box 129, Folder 3)
    - Department of the Interior: Water Pollution Administration Transfer from Health, Education and Welfare to the Department of the Interior. 1966 (Box 129, Folder 4-5)
    - Department of the Interior: Clippings, Stewart Udall. 1966 (Box 129, Folder 6)
    - Department of the Interior: Clippings, Cabinet and Staff. 1966 (Box 129, Folder 7)
    - Department of the Interior: Clippings, President Johnson. 1966 (Box 129, Folder 8)
    - Department of the Interior: Clippings, Politics. 1966 (Box 129, Folder 9)
    - Department of the Interior: Clippings, Vietnam. 1966 (Box 129, Folder 10)
    - Department of the Interior: Clippings, Miscellaneous. 1966 (Box 129, Folder 11)
    - Department of the Interior, 1966: Natural Resources Mission to Germany, March -10, 1966: Correspondence. 1966 (Box 130, Folder 1)
    - Department of the Interior: Natural Resources Mission to Germany, Itinerary. March 3-10, 1966 (Box 130, Folder 2)
    - Department of the Interior: Natural Resources Mission to Germany, Clippings and Press Coverage. 1966 (Box 130, Folder 3)
    - Department of the Interior: Natural Resources Mission to Germany, Photographs. 1966 (Box 130, Folder 4)
    - Department of the Interior: Natural Resources Mission to Germany, Report. 1966 (Box 130, Folder 5)
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies. January- March 1966 (Box 131, Folder 1)
      Arizona Newspapers Association Convention, Phoenix, Arizona, January 7, 1966
      American Mining Congress Meeting, Washington, DC, January 10, 1966
      President’s Conservation Awards Dinner, Washington, DC, January 11, 1966
      Memorial Service for Prime Minister Shastri of India, Washington Cathedral, Washington, DC, January 28, 1966
      Testimonial Dinner for Morris K. Udall, Tucson, Arizona, February 17, 1966
      Ground-breaking Ceremony for Job Corps Camp, Liberty State Park, New Jersey, February 24, 1966
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies-American Meteorological Society Annual Meeting, Denver, Colorado. January 26, 1966 (Box 131, Folder 2)
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies. April 1966 (Box 131, Folder 3)
      Presentation of National Teacher of the Year Award by President Johnson to Mrs. Mona Dayton of Tucson, Arizona, White House, April 4, 1966
      Presentation of Department of the Interior’s Conservation Service Award to Woody Guthrie, Washington, DC, April 6, 1966
      National Congress of American Indians and Bureau of Indian Affairs Directors Meeting, Santa Fe, New Mexico,April 14-15, 1966
      Women Doers Luncheon, Washington, DC, April 18, 1966
      Hike along the C. and O. Canal, Washington, DC, April April 23, 1966
      Swearing-in of Robert L. Bennett as Commissioner of Indian Affairs, White House, April 27, 1966
    - Department of the Interio: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies Western Governor’s Conference, Las Vegas, Nevada: Includes Tape Recording of Speech. April 25-26, 1966 (Box 131, Folder 4-6)
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies. May-June 1966 (Box 131, Folder 7)
      Includes::
      Annual Potomac River White Water Race, Washington, DC, May 1, 1966
      Reception celebrating transfer of Federal Water Pollution Control Administration from Health, Education and Welfare to the Department of the Interior, Washington, DC, May10, 1966
      Reception honoring Water Leaders of the Seven Colorado River Basin States, Washington, DC, May 11, 1966
      Long Island-Fire Island Trip, New York, May 27, 1966
      Hofstra University Natural Beauty Conference, Hempstead, New York, May 28, 1966. See Box 198: Honors and Awards and Box 177(Oversize)
      West Virginia Wesleyan College Commencement, Buckhannon, West Virginia, May 29, 1966. See Box 198: Honors and Awards
      Dedication of Cape Cod National Seashore, Eastham, Massachusetts, May 30, 1966
      "Open Mike"-Clear Channel National News Conference, WCCO Radio (Minneapolis-St. Paul), WHO (Des Moines), and KSL (Salt Lake City). Hour-long, phone-in radio broadcast.
      Utah State University Commencement, Logan, Utah, June 4, 1966. See Box 198: Honors and Awards
      Trip to Ottawa, Canada, June 23, 1966
      National Youth Conference on Natural Beauty and Conservation, Washington, DC, June 27, 1966
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies-Association of American Indian Affairs Annual Meeting, New York City. May 2, 1966 (Box 131, Folder 8)
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies-Annual Conference of Council on Foundations, Denver, Colorado. May 12, 1966 (Box 131, Folder 9)
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies-President Johnson’s Visit and Speech, Department of the Interior, Washington, DC. May 20, 1966 (Box 131, Folder 10)
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies-Dedication of Reston, Virginia. May 21, 1966 (Box 131, Folder 11)
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonie-Vermont Governor’s Conference on Natural Beauty ( Stowe Vermont) and Hike on Camel’s Hump. May 26, 1966 (Box 131, Folder 12)
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies Manufacturing Chemists Association Annual Conference, White Sulphur Springs, West Virginia. June 10, 1966 (Box 131, Folder 13)
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies-Lake Erie Water Pollution Control Enforcement Conference (Cleveland, Ohio) and Tour of the Cuyhoga River Valley Area. June 22, 1966 (Box 131, Folder 14)
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies. July August 1966 (Box 132, Folder 1)
      National Petroleum Council Dinner, Washington, DC, July 18, 1966
      Dedication of Gay Head as a National Landmark, Martha’s Vineyard, Massachusetts, July 30, 1966
      Meeting with Department employees after the swearing-in of Boyd Rasmussen as Director of the Bureau of Land Management, Washington, DC, August 3, 1966
      Ground-breaking at Test Facility South Bay Station of San Diego Gas Electric Co., Chula Vista, California, August 10, 1966
      Dedication and Inspection of the Rock Creek and Potomac Parkway Zoo By-Pass, Washington, DC, August 19, 1966
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies-Trip to Japan: United States-Japan Committee on Trade and Economic Affairs. July 19, 1966 (Box 132, Folder 2)
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies-Fifth Anniversary of the National Park Service, Washington, DC. D August 25, 1966 (Box 132, Folder 3)
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies. September 1966 (Box 132, Folder 4)
      Evening Program on the Mail, Washington, DC, September 11, 1966
      Governor’s Conference on Natural Beauty, Hershey, Pennsylvani, September 12, 1966
      Direct Dialing Conversation with the Virgin Islands, Washington, DC, September 15, 1966
      Vice-President’s Conference on Water Pollution Problems of the Great Lakes States, Chicago, Illinois, September 15-16, 1966
      Tour of the North Cascades, September 17-18, 1966
      Western States Power and Power Consumers Conference, Billings, Montana, September 26, 1966
      Dedication of the Platte-Winner Bridge, Platte, South Dakota, September 29, 1966
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies-Massachusetts Water Pollution Inspection Trip. September 6, 1966 (Box 132, Folder 5)
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies-Trip to the Great Falls of the Passaic River, Paterson, New Jersey.: Includes "Key to the City" from the Mayor, Mounted on Wooden Plaque. September 29, 1966 (Box 132, Folder 6)
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies October 1966 (Box 132, Folder 7)
      National Recreation and Park Association Prayer Breakfast, Washington, DC, October 10, 1966
      Signing Ceremony for Various Conservation Bills, White House, October 15, 1966
      Phoenix Press Club Forum, Phoenix, Arizona, October 17, 1966
      18th- Dedication of Hopi Tribal Industrial Park, Winslow, Arizona, October 18, 1966
      24th- Dedication of the Pacific Northwest Water Laboratory, Corvallis, Oregon, October 24, 1966
      27th- Dedication of Cabrillo National Monument, San Diego, California, October 27, 1966
      28th- Presentation of Beale Street National Historic Landmark, Memphis, Tennessee, October 28, 1966
      29th- York County Conservation Society Annual Meeting, York, Pennsylvania, October 29, 1966
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies-Dedication of Four Corners Power Plant, Farmington, New Mexico. October 11, 1966 (Box 132, Folder 8)
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies-Trip to Michigan: Tour of Pictured Rocks area; Speeches: Munising and Houghton. October 21-22, 1966 (Box 132, Folder 9)
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies-Symposium on Arid and Semi-arid Lands, Texas Technological College, Lubbock, Texas. October 31, 1966 (Box 132, Folder 10)
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies. November-December 1966 (Box 132, Folder 11)
      Presentation of Department of the Interior Conservation Service Awards, Washington, DC, November 10, 1966
      Texas State Historical Survey Committee Annual Convention, Fort Worth, Texa, December 2, 1966
      Dinner with Saturday Review editors, New York City, December 12, 1966
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies-Return of President Johnson from Asian and Pacific Tour, Dulles International Airport, Virginia. November 2, 1966 (Box 132, Folder 12)
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies-Public Relations Society of American National Conference, New York City. November 9, 1966 (Box 132, Folder 13)
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies-Stewart Udall's 6th Anniversary Celebration. December 7, 1966 (Box 132, Folder 14)
    - Department of the Interior: Speeches, Events, & Ceremonies-Christmas Tree Lighting, White Hous. December 15, 1966 (Box 132, Folder 15)
  - Department of the Interior, 1967-1968
    - Department of the Interior: 1967 Calendar. 1967 (Box 133, Folder 1)
    - Department of the Interior: Appointment Schedule. 1967 (Box 133, Folder 2-6)
    - Department of the Interior: Travel Accounts: Fiscal Year 1966/67. 1967 (Box 133, Folder 7)
    - Department of the Interior: Reports to the President. 1967 (Box 133, Folder 8)
    - Department of the Interior: "News and Possible New Makers", Memorandum to the President. 1967 (Box 133, Folder 9)
    - Department of the Interior: Stewart Udall and President Johnson. 1967 (Box 133, Folder 10)
    - Department of the Interior, 1967: Stewart Udall and President’s Staff. 1967 (Box 133, Folder 11)
    - Department of the Interior: Stewart Udall and Staff. 1967 (Box 134, Folder 1-2)
    - Department of the Interior: Jobs, Appointments, Letters of Recommendation. 1967 (Box 134, Folder 3)
    - Department of the Interior: Stewart Udall Personal and Miscellaneous Correspondence. 1967 (Box 134, Folder 4)
    - Department of the Interior: Photographs, Miscellaneous. 1967 (Box 134, Folder 5)
    - Department of the Interior: International Activities Assistant, Foreign Callers. 1967 (Box 134, Folder 6)
    - Department of the Interior: Miscellaneous Reports from Various Divisions. 1967 (Box 134, Folder 7)
    - Department of the Interior: Miscellaneous. 1967 (Box 134, Folder 8)
    - Department of the Interior: Robert McNamara: Correspondence. 1967 (Box 134, Folder 9)
    - Department of the Interior: Water for Peace, Jordan River, etc. 1967 (Box 134, Folder 10)
    - Department of the Interior: Press Conferences. 1967 (Box 134, Folder 11-14)
    - Department of the Interior: Cabinet Meetings. 1967 (Box 135, Folder 1)
    - Department of the Interior: Stewart Udall Notes and Comments. 1967 (Box 135, Folder 2-3)
    - Department of the Interior: President’s State of the Union Message. January 10, 1967 (Box 135, Folder 4)
    - Department of the Interior: Morris K. Udall and Viet Nam. 1967 (Box 135, Folder 5)